Kaustubh Dutta

+1 (873)-288-1552 | kdutta2511@gmail.com | 3-386 Chapel Street, Ottawa K1N 7Z6 | LinkedIn | IEEEXplore

OBJECTIVE

Having more than three years of experience in Software, UI/UX Development and currently pursuing my Master's in University of Ottawa, I have keen interest in Optimized Coding and seeing myself as a Full Stack Developer. I am truly fascinated about Business Intelligence and the way our mankind is progressing towards the achievement of an infinite paradise of knowledge but with a concern of Data theft and Data Hygiene.

EDUCATION

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.

Master's in E- Business Technologies

KIIT University, India May 2016 GPA: 8.64/10

Bachelor's in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

SKILLS

Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, Hadoop, Hive, Pig

Programming Languages: Java, Python, R, SQL, SAS, Perl, VBA Macros

Data Mining & Visualization Tools: Advanced Excel, SAS Enterprise Miner, Tableau, Qlik View, Power BI, XLStat

Statistical Methods and Machine Learning Concepts: Linear and Logistic Regression, Market Basket Analysis, Text Mining

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nokia | Business Systems Analyst - Intern | Ottawa, Canada

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

April 2020

GPA: 8.71/10.0

- Analyzing Service Level Agreements using DAX and Power Queries in PowerBI which helped in tracking Incoming Tickets, KPI's and Target Resolution Days of Common Software Foundation of Nokia Software (NSW).
- Writing Perl Scripts to develop automated Cron Jobs to fetch data using Curl API from JIRA that helped in creating automated Power BI reports under less than a minute.
- Experienced in hosting Maria DB and development in Unix Server.

Nokia | Project Management Assistant - COOP | Ottawa, Canada

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

- Derived critical insights and KPI Calculations using VBA Macros and Pivot Tables which helped in tracking and updating key project artifacts.
- Managed and supported Confluence and SharePoint web portals for UI/UX improvements.

Capgemini Technology Services | Senior Software Engineer | India

May 2016 – June 2018

- As a Business Analyst, created user stories to translate stakeholder requirements using Gherkin language in Excel and increased the rate of product delivery from 15% to 30% by automating the script.
- Drafted and maintained business requirements from clients and aligned them with functional and technical requirements thereby ensuring smooth workflow process.
- As a full stack developer, developed prototype concepts using prototyping tools like Axure, Justinmind and developed singular page applications from UI designs using Angular JS on top of Spring Boot Backend.
- Designed a new prototyping tool for UI developers using Angular 5 under ADC that resulted in time saving of 20-22 man hours / week.
- Experienced in SDLC process under both Agile and waterfall methodology.

Reliance Jio | LTE Network Engineer - Intern | India

May 2015 - June 2015

- LTE Network Architecture & Frame Structure through Cellular Call Management & Small Cell Planning.
- OFDM Downlink & SC-FDMA Uplink designing of base stations using QAM Modulation for enhanced security.

SIEMENS NETWORKS | Automation Engineer-Intern | India

May 2014 - July 2014

- Softstarters, Plotting & Analysis of Torque-Speed and Speed-Current curves using ABB Prosoft of 110, 160 & 220 kW motors.
- SIEMENS SIMARIS Curves & Tripping Characteristics using SIMOCODE- Dynamic & Powerful Smart Motor Management System.
- Diesel Generator Sizing for the calculation of supplying emergency power to essential loads.
- Calculation of phase correction in AC circuits to reduce voltage and current phase difference by using Capacitor Banks.

ACADEMIC & INDUSTRIAL PROJECTS

Hyperledger Framework in Blockchain applications (Master's Project)

- Based on Hyper Ledger Fabric to track vehicular details and ownership history.
- Used Javascript to create the Ledger, JSON to track the information and deployed the application in AWS.

Smart Banking application using full stack technologies

- Developed smart banking application like a net banking app during my time in Capgemini.
- Used Java, AngularJS to develop back end and front-end application.

Online retail database using SQL

- Designed database taking care of ERD and data integrity using DDL Scripts
- Performed database programming and performance tuning using Indexing

LEADERSHIP AND AWARDS

- Winner in the How to Change the World organized by Ontario Society of Professional Engineers, Feb 2020
- Finalist in CANDEV data challenge, 2020 organized by Statistics, Canada
- Head coordinator of Future Leaders Club that is like Toastmasters club in University of Ottawa.
- Won "Pat on the Back" Employee award FY2017 for reducing the time to market in Capgemini.
- Stood first in Kodathon2K13 coding competition held at KIIT University, 2013.

CERTIFICATIONS AND RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

Blockchain, March 2018 | Machine Learning and Al, March 2018 | Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certified, July 2019